0000-0003-0633-5429 
olegolikh@knu.ua

Serhiy Kondratenko
0000-0002-4403-7732
kondratenko@knu.ua

Datsenko, Oleksandr 
0000-0002-4461-1925

lesoto8g@gmail.com
kondratenko@knu.ua


olikh - user name  
e2662421O%





Dr. Hab.

defects
solar cell
ultrasound
metaheuristic algorithms
semiconductor structures


Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, Kyiv, Ukraine
64/13, Volodymyrska Street
01601


------------------------------
Chang
Sun
Research School of Electrical, Energy & Materials Engineering, 
Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2601, Australia
chang.sun@anu.edu.au
His papers are devoted to defect in silicon 
(IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics, 2023, 13(4), pp. 524–534,
Physica Status Solidi-RRL, 2021, 15(12), 2000520)


Xuegong 
Yu
State Key Laboratory of Silicon Materials and Department of Materials Science and Engineering, 
Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China
yuxuegong@zju.edu.cn
He is skilled in properties of FeB pair in silicon
{AIP ADVANCES 3, 082124 (2013),
Journal of Crystal Growth, 2024, 630, 127602,
International Journal of Photoenergy, 2015, 154574}


Nabil 
Khelifati
Research Center in Semiconductor Technology for the Energetic, 
Development of Semiconductor Conversion Devices
Algeria
Centre de Recherche en Technologie des Semi-Conducteurs pour l’Energétique
Algiers, Algeria

n.khelifati@gmail.com, khelifatinabil@crtse.dz
He studies defects in silicon
(Physica Status Solidi A, 2019, 216(17), 1900253,
Materials Research Express, 2019, 6(5), 055907)


Karsten 
Bothe
Institute for Solar Energy Research Hamelin (ISFH), 
Am Ohrberg 1, 31860 Emmerthal, Germany
k.bothe@isfh.de
He is a leading expert in the field of the influence of defects on the properties of silicon solar cells
(Semiconductor Science and Technology, 2019, 34(3), 035030,
IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics, 2021, 11(4), pp. 890–896, 9435415,
Solar RRL, 2023, 7(13), 2300240,
Solar RRL, 2024, 8(3), 2300873)


Hele 
Savin
Department of Micro- and Nanosciences
Aalto University
02150 Espoo, Finland
ville.vahanissi@aalto.fi 
His papers are devoted to iron and other defects in silicon solar cell
(IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics, 2020, 10(6), pp. 1532–1537, 9157971,
Physica Status Solidi A, 2019, 216(17), 1900253,
)


Ziv 
Hameiri
School of Photovoltaic and Renewable Energy Engineering, 
University of New South Wales, Sydney, NSW 2052, Australia
ziv.hameiri@unsw.edu.au
He has a great skill in defect in silicon
(Physica Status Solidi-RRL, 2021, 15(12), 2000520,
Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells, 2023, 251, 112121,
Advanced Science, 2023, 10(18), 2300206)

--------------------------------------------------------------------------
Influence of Illumination Spectrum on Dissociation Kinetics of Iron-boron Pairs in Silicon


Photo-dissociation kinetics of iron–boron (FeB) pairs in boron-doped Czochralski silicon was studied experimentally using different light sources.
It was shown that the FeB dissociation rate depends not only on integrated light intensity and overall carrier generation rate, but also on spectral composition of illumination.
The value of the material constant of dissociation K varies and has been determined to be within (1.5-3.8) fs.
The investigation has revealed an increase in the dissociation rate with increase in photon energy.
The results indicate that recombination-enhanced defect reaction is the primary factor in the second stage of pair dissociation.


silicon; iron-boron pairs; light-induced dissociation; wavelength impact; dissociation rate

------------------------------------------------------------------------------
What is the novelty of this work?

This study aims to compare the effectiveness of parameter estimation using the opposed two-diode model, employing 14 different meta-heuristic algorithms, and determine the best-performing algorithm among them.

короткий варіант (до 150 символів)
The paper evaluates the effectiveness of 14 meta-heuristic algorithms for solar cell parameter estimation using the opposed two-diode model



Why do you think the paper is important?

The IV characteristics of new- generation photovoltaic devices often show an S-shaped deformation. Accurately determining parameters for such systems is crucial for applications


Why the journal should publish it?

We strongly believe that study, which involves testing and comparative analysis of different meta-heuristic algorithms for estimating solar cell parameters, will be of great interest to the readers




The study reported is relevant to the scope of the journal or its audience.

The research concerns the determining of solar cell parameters thus it is relevant to the journal's scope and audience.



The study addresses problems or issues with significant impact and broad readership; the study is worth doing and reporting.

The obtained results pertain to various new-generation photovoltaic devices, including thin-film, organic, perovskite, and quantum dot solar cells.



The development and design of the experiment, instrument or model are sufficiently described or referenced, and are sufficiently detailed to permit the study to be replicated.

The method used to obtain the presented results is described in sufficient detail to permit the study to be replicated.



The data set is sufficiently described or the data source referenced.

The method of data acquisition is described in detail.


The conclusion of the study reported clearly addresses the stated objective of the study.

The research objective and the study conclusions are coherent.
The stated research objective is to compare the effectiveness of various metaheuristic methods in determining the parameters of solar cells. The conclusions assert that EBLSHADE and TLBO are effective in accurately determining parameter values in most cases.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Шановні колеги!

Надсилаю узагальнення отриманих за вашою допомогою результатів.
Сподіваюсь на зауваження та дозвіл для надсилання до редакції.

У випадку вашого позитивного рішення, чи правильно я розумію,
що під час оформлення можна буде користуватися е-адресами, на які я зараз надсилаю листа
та 
0000-0002-4403-7732
0000-0002-4461-1925
?

З повагою,
Оліх Олег