Sandra 
Herlufsen
Institute for Solar Energy Research Hamelin, Emmerthal, Germany
herlufsen@isfh.de
She is skilled in defect transformation in silicon solar cells
(Phys. Status Solidi RRL 6 (2012)  1–3,
IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 11 (2021) 890-896)


Nabil 
Khelifati
Centre de Recherche en Technologie des Semi-conducteurs pour l’Energétique, Algiers, Algeria
n.khelifati@gmail.com
His papers are devoted to dissociation and formation of iron–boron pairs in
silicon.
(Phys. Status Solidi A 216 (2019) 1900253,
Journal of Electronic Materials 45 (2016), 5621-5625)


Fiacre 
E. 
Rougieux
School of Photovoltaic and Renewable Energy Engineering, The University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia
ﬁacre.rougieux@unsw.edu.au
He is a specialist in the physics of defects in silicon 
(Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells 187 (2018) 263–272,
IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 11 (2021), 273-281)


Andriy
B.
Romanyuk
Institute of Physics
University of Basel, Switzerland
andriy.romanyuk@unibas.ch
He is author of works, which are deals with acoustically induced effects in semiconductors.
(J. Appl. Phys. 107 (2010)
114307; J. Appl. Phys. 99 (2006), 034314; Appl. Phys. Lett. 90 (2007),
013118)


Arthur
Medvids
Faculty of Materials Science and Applied Chemistry, 
Riga Technical University, Riga, Latvia
He has investigated ultrasound influence on semiconductor structure
medvids@latnet.lv
(Phys Status Solidi C 13(2016), 793–797)




Smagul 
Zh
Karazhanov 
Senior Scientist    
Institute for Energy Technology, Norway
Sector Energy and Environmental Technology
smagulk@ife.no
His papers are devoted to ultrasound-dislocation interaction in silicon barrier structure.
(J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys. 41 (2008) 165107; J. Phys. Chem. Solids 70 (2009) 989–992)

Bruno
K.
Meyer
Physical Institute
Justus-Liebig Universitaty, Germany
Bruno.K.Meyer@exp1.physik.uni-giessen.de
He has investigated ultrasound influence on semiconductor structure
(Solid State Commun. 116 (2000) 87–91)

Silke
Steingrube
Department Solar Energy, Institute Solid-State Physics, Leibniz University of Hannover, Appelstr. 2, 30167
Hannover, Germany
steingrube@solar.uni-hannover.de
He has used models of coupled defect level recombination to explain features of solar cell current-voltage characteristics.
(J. Appl. Phys. 110(2011), 014515)


Vishnu
Gopal
Solid State Physics Laboratory, Timarpur, Delhi
110054, India
sspl@ssplnet.org
He has introduced model of dislocation–induced impedance, which has been used in our manuscript.
(IEEE Trans Electron Devices 50(2003), 1220–1226; IEEE Trans Electron Devices 51(2004),1078–1083)

