0000-0003-0633-5429 
olegolikh@knu.ua


plyt2007@gmail.com
https://orcid.org/my-orcid?orcid=0000-0002-0131-9860



V E Lashkaryov Institute of Semiconductor Physics NAS of Ukraine, Kyiv, Ukraine

Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, Kyiv, Ukraine


Microwave induced transformation of defect in SiC and GaAs



The influence of microwave radiation (2.45 GHz, 1.5 W/cm$^2$, up to 80~s) on defects was studied in single crystals $n$-6H–SiC, $n$-GaAs and epi-GaAs.
The capture cross-section of charge carrier have been found to change
and defect complexes to be reconstructed due to the growing number of  interstitial atoms in the near surface layer.
The correlation between the changes in defect sub-system and deformation of the near surface layer is analyzed.
The possible mechanisms of the revealed effects are discussed.



Duncan 
H. 
Gregory
University of Glasgow,
School of Chemistry, Glasgow G12 8QQ, United Kingdom
Duncan.Gregory@Glasgow.ac.uk
He is skilled in Microwave method
(Chem. Rev. 114 (2014) 1170–1206)


Haiyan 
Ou
Technical University of Denmark, Department of Photonics Engineering, Lyngby, Denmark
haou@fotonik.dtu.dk
His papers are devoted to defect in SiC.
(J. Appl. Phys. 124 (2018) 054901;
Optical Materials Express 9 (2019) 295)



S. 
Sasaki
Department of Electronic Science and Engineering, 
Kyoto University, Katsura, Nishikyo, Kyoto 615-8510, Japan
sasaki@semicon.kuee.kyoto-u.ac.jp
He investigates the deep levels in semiconductor 
(J. Appl. Phys. 109 (2011) 013705;
Appl. Phys. Lett 102 (2013) 032104;)





Використані:
Andriy Romanyuk (University of Basel), 
Sandra Herlufsen (ISFH), 
Nabil Khelifati (Centre de Recherche en Technologie des Semi-conducteurs pour l'Energétique), 
Arthur Medvids (Riga Technical University), 
Fiacre Rougieux (University of New South Wales)
___________________________________________________________


Sandra 
Herlufsen
Institute for Solar Energy Research Hamelin, Emmerthal, Germany
herlufsen@isfh.de
She is skilled in defect transformation in silicon solar cells
(Phys. Status Solidi RRL 6 (2012)  1–3,
IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 11 (2021) 890-896)


Nabil 
Khelifati
Centre de Recherche en Technologie des Semi-conducteurs pour l’Energétique, Algiers, Algeria
n.khelifati@gmail.com
His papers are devoted to dissociation and formation of iron–boron pairs in
silicon.
(Phys. Status Solidi A 216 (2019) 1900253,
Journal of Electronic Materials 45 (2016), 5621-5625)


Fiacre 
E. 
Rougieux
School of Photovoltaic and Renewable Energy Engineering, The University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia
ﬁacre.rougieux@unsw.edu.au
He is a specialist in the physics of defects in silicon 
(Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells 187 (2018) 263–272,
IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 11 (2021), 273-281)


Andriy
B.
Romanyuk
Institute of Physics
University of Basel, Switzerland
andriy.romanyuk@unibas.ch
He is author of works, which are deals with acoustically induced effects in semiconductors.
(J. Appl. Phys. 107 (2010)
114307; J. Appl. Phys. 99 (2006), 034314; Appl. Phys. Lett. 90 (2007),
013118)


Arthur
Medvids
Faculty of Materials Science and Applied Chemistry, 
Riga Technical University, Riga, Latvia
He has investigated ultrasound influence on semiconductor structure
medvids@latnet.lv
(Phys Status Solidi C 13(2016), 793–797)




Smagul 
Zh
Karazhanov 
Senior Scientist    
Institute for Energy Technology, Norway
Sector Energy and Environmental Technology
smagulk@ife.no
His papers are devoted to ultrasound-dislocation interaction in silicon barrier structure.
(J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys. 41 (2008) 165107; J. Phys. Chem. Solids 70 (2009) 989–992)

Bruno
K.
Meyer
Physical Institute
Justus-Liebig Universitaty, Germany
Bruno.K.Meyer@exp1.physik.uni-giessen.de
He has investigated ultrasound influence on semiconductor structure
(Solid State Commun. 116 (2000) 87–91)

Silke
Steingrube
Department Solar Energy, Institute Solid-State Physics, Leibniz University of Hannover, Appelstr. 2, 30167
Hannover, Germany
steingrube@solar.uni-hannover.de
He has used models of coupled defect level recombination to explain features of solar cell current-voltage characteristics.
(J. Appl. Phys. 110(2011), 014515)


Vishnu
Gopal
Solid State Physics Laboratory, Timarpur, Delhi
110054, India
sspl@ssplnet.org
He has introduced model of dislocation–induced impedance, which has been used in our manuscript.
(IEEE Trans Electron Devices 50(2003), 1220–1226; IEEE Trans Electron Devices 51(2004),1078–1083)

