Ref: SM_2019_1528
Title: Relationship between the ideality factor and the iron concentration in silicon solar cells
Journal: Superlattices and Microstructures

Dear Dr. Olikh,

Thank you for submitting your manuscript to Superlattices and Microstructures. I have received comments from reviewers on your manuscript. Your paper should become acceptable for publication pending suitable minor revision and modification of the article in light of the appended reviewer comments.

When resubmitting your manuscript, please carefully consider all issues mentioned in the reviewers' comments, outline every change made point by point, and provide suitable rebuttals for any comments not addressed.

To submit your revised manuscript:

    Log into EVISE® at: http://www.evise.com/evise/faces/pages/navigation/NavController.jspx?JRNL_ACR=SM
    Locate your manuscript under the header 'My Submissions that need Revisions' on your 'My Author Tasks' view
    Click on 'Agree to Revise'
    Make the required edits
    Click on 'Complete Submission' to approve

What happens next?

After you approve your submission preview you will receive a notification that the submission is complete. To track the status of your paper throughout the editorial process, log in to EVISE® at: http://www.evise.com/evise/faces/pages/navigation/NavController.jspx?JRNL_ACR=SM.

Enrich your article to present your research with maximum impact. This journal supports the following Content Innovations:

I look forward to receiving your revised manuscript as soon as possible.

Kind regards,

Dr. Ma
Managing Editor
Superlattices and Microstructures

Comments from the editors and reviewers:
-Reviewer 1

  -

In this paper author has used the two--diode model to investigate the relationship of diode ideality factor and the iron concentration in silicon n+ − p solar cells by computer simulation for temperature range of 290-340 K. Author shows that the ideality factor value can be used to estimate the impurity concentration, energy level and capture cross–section in silicon solar cells. Author has done the systematic analyses to support his findings. This manuscript is well written by analysing the theoretical model. It is important to publish this paper for the silicon PV technology. I recommend publishing this manuscript after some minor amendment as follows:   

      (i)                 Correct the sign 290 ÷ 330 K in page 2

(ii)              Some grammatical errors

(iii)            Define the mT, MA, γ and Eef in the Table 1 caption in page 7.



-Reviewer 2

  -

This paper describes a study, based on computer  simulation and the two–diode model, to obtain the ideality factor value of silicon n+p solar cells with iron contaminants, for different temperatures. I consider the manuscript interesting. The results obtained are interpreted correctly. However, a minor revision is required. In my opinion, the author should refine the manuscript, considering the following points:

1) Detailed information about the value of the main parameters taken into simulation (SCAPS) should be given in the text.

2) I recommend including a more detailed analysis on how the parameters n, I01, and I02 have been calculated from Eq. (4). 