Subject:   	JAP: MS #J-DIS17-17-5066 Decision Letter
From:   	jap-edoffice@aip.org
Date:   	Fri, October 6, 2017 9:38 pm
To:   	olikh@univ.kiev.ua
Cc:   	olikholeg@gmail.com
Priority:   	Normal
Options:   	View Full Header | View Printable Version  | Download this as a file

Dear Dr. Olikh:

Your manuscript, referenced below, has been reviewed for publication in the Journal of Applied Physics. I am pleased to inform you that it has received positive reviewer comments.

"Acousto-defect interaction in irradiated and non-irradiated silicon n+-p-structure"
J-DIS17-17-5066

However, based on reviewer comments, the recommendation is minor revisions. His/her comments are included below and/or are attached.

Please indicate how the manuscript has been revised in your response letter so that the editors can see whether you have complied with the reviewer comments.

The revised manuscript should be returned to the Editor promptly. Your revised manuscript is due 04-Nov-2017. A manuscript returned after 04-Nov-2017 will generally be regarded as new submission and will be assigned a new receipt date.

Please go to the URL below to submit the revised version. To meet AIP Production requirements, please provide a separate figure file for each cited figure number (all parts in one file), in addition to your article-text file.
https://jap.peerx-press.org/cgi-bin/main.plex?el=A2N7Fdaw7A7FVoL6I7A9ftdhp6Gr2dktTW4Crc4MzjgY
(If clicking on the above URL address directly from your mail program is unsuccessful, please copy and paste the complete address into your browser.)

If you have not done so already, please download the License to Publish form (URL below), sign, and return it to the Editorial Office of Journal of Applied Physics.

If you have any questions, feel free to contact us at jap-edoffice@aip.org.

Sincerely yours,

Andreas Mandelis, FRSC, FCAE, FAPS, FSPIE, FAAAS, FASME, PhD
Professor and Canada Research Chair (Tier 1)
Director, Center for Advanced Diffusion-Wave and Photoacoustic Technologies
Dept. of Mechanical and Industrial Engineering
Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering
Institute of Biomaterials and Biomedical Engineering
University of Toronto
5 King's College Road
Toronto, ON M5S 3G8
CANADA
www.mie.utoronto.ca/cadift

Journal of Applied Physics Editorial Office

AIP Publishing
1305 Walt Whitman Road
Suite 300
Melville, NY 11747-4300 USA

phone: +1-516-576-2910
e-mail: jap-edoffice@aip.org


---------------------------------------------------------------------
Manuscript #J-DIS17-17-5066:

* Acceptable article source files for your revised paper are Word or Latex/ReVTeX. Please replace your PDF file with an acceptable article source file. If you are having conversion issues, you may keep the PDF as the article file and upload the article source file using the "Additional Information for Reviewer" file type. This will allow a quicker handoff to the production team if the paper is accepted.



***PLEASE NOTE****
The appearance of your by-line and your author order of your data and your text is EXACTLY the way it will be printed. Review it carefully NOW to ensure you are completely satisfied. No modifications will be accepted in the event your article is to be accepted for publication. Please make any needed changes promptly.
******************
Editor's Comments:


Reviewer Comments:
Reviewer #1 Evaluations:
Does the manuscript present original and timely results that significantly advance the knowledge in applied physics: Yes
Does the manuscript report on convincing and rigorous data methods and analysis: Yes
Is the manuscript clearly written in correct English well organized and free from ambiguities: No
Is the title descriptive of the contents concise interesting and free of acronyms: Yes
Does the abstract adequately and clearly describe the contents (problem approach findings) of the paper: Yes
Are the figures in the manuscript necessary adequate well presented and clearly labeled: Yes
Is the reference list appropriate: Yes

Reviewer #1 (REMARKS to AUTHOR(s)):

The manuscript presents detailed comparisons of the electrical characteristics between irradiated and pristine Si homojunctions under ultrasonication loading. The authors discuss not only the results of IV characteristics phenomenally, but further provide possible mechanisms and defects analysis. The findings are interesting and certainly open a new way of tuning the properties of silicon based electronics.

However, I have following comments for authors:

1. The authors point out multiple times that the ultrasonic loading discussed in the manuscript does not induce permanent annealing effects on the samples and thus the results are fully reversible. However, there is not data supporting this argument. Also how long does it take for the system to relax back to its original state and how well? A cyclic loading-unloading graph may be helpful to clarify this point.

2. It is understandable that the authors would like to "keep the volume of this paper at an rather reasonable size" in the defects analysis section, but I wonder if those important data can be appendiced as supplementary information?

3. Why is g6SC sample missing the 0.2 Wus (W/cm2) experimental data?

4. Can the authors comment on the effect of ultrasound frequency on the sample?

5. In figure (a),"The dashed, dot-dashed and dotted lines in (a) are the base, SCR and shunt components of iSC current, respectively." are those calculated curves or experimental? Under what conditions?

6. In figure 5 "Axis |uD + uA| corresponds to δ = 0◦ case, whereas axis |uD + uA| corresponds to δ = 180◦ case.", The first "|uD + uA|" should probably be "|uD - uA|".

7. The language could be polished more. There are some sentences that may cause confusions, for example in the abstract: "The effects of reactor neutrons and 60Co gamma radiation on ultrasound influence were studied." makes one wonder if the radiation is acting on the Si crystal or the ultrasound; Some grammar mistakes, such as ". One can recognize, that τn effected mainly by CiOi and vacancy clusters in γ- and neutron-irradiated samples,"



Reviewer #2 Evaluations:
Does the manuscript present original and timely results that significantly advance the knowledge in applied physics: Yes
Does the manuscript report on convincing and rigorous data methods and analysis: Yes
Is the manuscript clearly written in correct English well organized and free from ambiguities: Yes
Is the title descriptive of the contents concise interesting and free of acronyms: Yes
Does the abstract adequately and clearly describe the contents (problem approach findings) of the paper: Yes
Are the figures in the manuscript necessary adequate well presented and clearly labeled: Yes
Is the reference list appropriate: Yes

Reviewer #2 (REMARKS to AUTHOR(s)):

The manuscript "Acousto-defect interaction in irradiated and non-irradiated silicon n+-p-structure" reports on the influence of ultrasound on the electrical performance of Si n+-p structure via acousto-defect interaction. The authors studied the acoustically induced effects on samples with different kinds of defects generated by different irradiation sources accordingly. The authors found that ultrasound can reversibly tune the minority carrier lifetime, shunt resistance, SCR carrier lifetime and the ideality factor by changing the carrier capture coefficient of defects and coupling effect between distant defects. These results are novel and provide valuable insight to controlling defect functionality via an external source. Thus I recommend the manuscript to be published on Journal of Applied Physics.
