home2 token
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




The authors carried out MWT experiments on differently doped SiC or GaAs.
Did the concentration of dopants change the evolution of point defects?
The Fermi level is different for differently doped hosts,
which charge states of intrinsic defects and MWT-induced defects, and thus the interaction, may be different.
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------


The calculation showed that the Fermi level $E_F$ is (75-100)~meV below 
the bottom of the conduction band $E_C$ in SiC samples.
$E_F-E_C$ is about 65~mEV in GAS2 sample.
GAT and GAS1 samples, epi-structure substrates are degenerate, and 
the Fermi level is in the conduction band.
Ostensibly under such conditions, 
all detected deep levels have to be filled; 
therefore, they can not participate in acoustoelectric interaction at all.
However, the above evaluations are correct for semiconductors' bulk.
The near-surface (or interface) bending of band leads to an increase in energy distance between
$E_F$ and $E_C$.
As a result, investigated levels  are empty under equilibrium conditions.
The alternating piezoelectric field leads to both filling of levels 
and arising of transverse acoustoelectric voltage.
Thus the concentration of dopants is not determinative 
for charge states of intrinsic defects and MWT-induced defects
in contrast to the near-surface charge.
The investigation did not show 
the essential dependence of the influence of MW treatment on doping levels as well.



--------------------------------------------------------------------------

The Pool-Frenkel effect is related to defect states of dislocations.
Yes, some works dealt the interaction between irradiation-induced point defects and dislocations,
such as Appl. Phys. Lett. 117, 023501 (2020) and J. Mater. Chem. C 9, 3177 (2021).
But I didn’t see any detailed discussion in this work.





























\cite{TAV:1992ZnSeGaAsphoto,TAV:2003MIS_hetero,TAV:1989hetero,TAV:1993general,TAV:1991SiSiO2,TAV:1989SiGaAsnodefect,
TAV:1991gener,TAV:1999GaAs_AlGaAs,TAV:1993MIS,TAV:1991SiMOS,TAV:1993GaAs,OstrovPAN,OlikhSSC,OstrovskiiSST}

A-DLTS \cite{TAV:2003MIS_hetero,TAV:1999GaAs_AlGaAs,TAV:1993MIS,TAV:1991SiMOS}


TAV  spectroscopies have been extensively performed in 
the past to characterize variety of  semiconductors and their 
interfaces. The most important studies include the detection 
of  bulk and bound excitons in GaAs, characterization of 
the  interface between  the GaAs and  its anodic oxide,
liquid  junction solar cells,  and detection of  impurity levels 
in GaAs, InP, InAs, CdS, Si, Hgl-xCdxTel/CdTe and All_xGaxAs/GaAs quantum wells 
and  superlattices.  Here  we  only  report  some  results  on 
All x GaxAs/GaAs  quantum  wells  and Hg1xCdxTe/CdTe,
\cite{TAV:1991gener}




Acousto-electric  deep  level  transient  spectroscopy 
(AEDLTS)  can  be  used  with  a  large  variety  of 
external  excitations  to  study  deep  trap  levels  in  semi- 
conductors. \cite{TAV:1993GaAs}



\vspace{1cm}
\noindent
\textcolor[rgb]{0.00,0.50,1.00}{\textbf{Comment~3.}}
\emph{The adopted deep level observation techniuqe is not so common,
and it is difficult to judge measurement accuracy.
For confirmation of the results, conventional techniques such as DLTS should be employed simultaneously.}

In fact, DLTS-related techniques, designed for deep level characterization,
are numerous and most widely used.
Unfortunately, we are currently unable to apply the DLTS method.
But it should be noted the transverse acoustoelectric voltage (TAV)
has been extensively performed to characterize variety of  semiconductors and their 
interfaces
\cite{TAV:1992ZnSeGaAsphoto,TAV:2003MIS_hetero,TAV:1989hetero,TAV:1993general,TAV:1991SiSiO2,TAV:1989SiGaAsnodefect,
TAV:1991gener,TAV:1999GaAs_AlGaAs,TAV:1993MIS,TAV:1991SiMOS,TAV:1993GaAs,OstrovPAN,OlikhSSC,OstrovskiiSST}.
The most important studies include the  
characterization of the  interface between  the GaAs and  its anodic oxide, 
and detection of  defect levels 
in GaAs, InP, InAs, CdS, Si crystals, 
Hg$_{l-x}$Cd$_x$Tel\/CdTe, ZnSe\/GaAs, Si\/SiO$_2$ heterostructures,
Si MOS--structures,
epi-GaAs,
and Al$_{1-x}$Ga$_x$As\/GaAs quantum wells 
\cite{TAV:1991gener,TAV:1992ZnSeGaAsphoto,TAV:1991SiSiO2,OlikhSSC,TAV:1993MIS,1999GaAs_AlGaAs}.
The  principle of TAV  spectroscopy closely coincides with the idea  of  the original  DLTS 
technique; as a result, the names
``acoustic  deep-level  transient spectroscopy 
(A-DLTS)''
 \cite{TAV:2003MIS_hetero,TAV:1999GaAs_AlGaAs,TAV:1993MIS,TAV:1991SiMOS} 
or ``acousto-electric  deep  level  transient  spectroscopy 
(AEDLTS)'' 
\cite{TAV:1993GaAs}
are used this method as well.
Besides, the acoustoelectric transient spectroscopy has some strengths over the original  DLTS.
First, DLTS requires the measurement over a wide temperature range 
in the case of the presence of defects, which differ significantly in a level location.
TAV spectroscopy needs a much narrower temperature range.
Second, the acoustoelectric transient spectroscopy does not require barrier formation.
On the one hand, the rectified contact formation can influence the defect subsystem 
in the near-surface region before\/after microwave processing.
On the other hand, the presence of metal contact before irradiation 
significantly affects the penetration of electromagnetic waves into the semiconductor.
Third, the TAV method permits the detection of traps at the 
epi–layer and substrate interface \cite{OstrovPAN,OlikhSSC,OstrovskiiSST}.
The last two features were notably essential in our case.
 



Застосування нейронних мереж для визначення концентрації заліза в кремнієвих сонячних елементах 
Application of neural networks to determine the iron concentration in silicon solar cells


This study aimed
Summary of  the  trap parameters detected by  the A-DLTS in Si-MOS structures 




