

Dr.
Rachel 
C. 
Kurchin
Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, USA
rkurchin@alum.mit.edu
Her papers are devoted to extract defect properties from inexpensive
IV measurements of completed devices
(IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 10 (2020) 1532-1537)



Prof.
Carlos 
del Cañizo
Instituto de Energía Solar, Universidad Politécnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain
Carlos.canizo@ies.upm.es
His papers are devoted to extract defect properties from inexpensive
IV measurements of completed devices
(IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 10 (2020) 1532-1537)


Prof.
Junichiro
Shiomi
Department of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan
shiomi@photon.t.u-tokyo.ac.jp
His research interests focus on materials informatics, which combines material property calculations/
measurements and informatics algorithms.
(Journal of Applied Physics, 128 (2020) 161102,
ACS Combinatorial Science 22 (2020) 782-790,
Nanoscale and Microscale Thermophysical Engineering 23 (2019) 157-172)

Dr.
Xinbo 
Zou
School of Information Science and Technology, Shanghai Tech University, Shanghai, China
zouxb@shanghaitech.edu.cn
His papers are devoted to using ideality factor as the numerical indicator of 
semiconductor barrier structure inhomogeneity
(Applied Physics Letters 116 (2020) 062102 )


Prof.
Sergey 
V.
Bulyarskiy
Institute of Nanotechnology of Microelectronics of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Moscow, Russia
bulyar2954@mail.ru
His papers are devoted to defect characterization by using current-votage measurements
(Journal of Applied Physics, 128 (2020) 155702,
Solid State Electronics 160 (2019) 107624)


Prof.
Songyou
Y.
Wang
Shanghai Ultra-Precision Optical Manufacturing Engineering Center and Department of Optical Science and Engineering, 
Fudan University, Shanghai, China.
songyouwang@fudan.edu.cn
His papers are devoted to numerical simulations of photovoltaic effect in silicon solar cell
(Renewable Energy 77 (2015) 442-446)


Prof.
Ashraf
Uddin
School of Photovoltaic and Renewable Energy Engineering, 
University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia
a.uddin@unsw.edu.au
He has investigated the using of ideality factor to estimate the recombination in solar cell
(IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 8  (2018) 1701-1709) 



Keith 
R. 
McIntosh
PV Lighthouse, Coledale, Australia
krmcintosh@pvlighthouse.com.au
He is author of works, which are deals with relationship between ideality factor and traps.
(16th European Photovoltaic Solar Energy Conference: Proceedings (2000) 250-253, 
Mater. Sol. Cells 117 (2013) 251-258)


Ziv 
Hameiri
Solar Energy Research Institute of Singapore, National University of Singapore, Singapore
ziv.hameiri@gmail.com
He has a great skill in evaluation of recombination processes by using ideality factor
(Mater. Sol. Cells 117 (2013) 251-258)



Prof.
Wim 
C. 
Sinke
University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam,  Netherlands
w.c.sinke@uva.nl.
His papers are devoted to the investigation of ideality factor value 
(Progress in Photovoltaics: Research and Applications 13 (2005) 3-16)

Prof.
A. Aissat
Faculty of Technology University of Blida, Blida, Algeria
sakre23@yahoo.fr 
He has a great skill in solar cell simulation
(Superlattices Microstruct. 138 (2020) 106377)



Prof.
Nouredine
Sengouga
Laboratory of Metallic and Semiconducting Materials, Université de Biskra, Biskra, Algeria
n.sengouga@univ-biskra.dz
He has a great skill in solar cell simulation
(Radiat. Phys. Chem. 123 (2016) 103-108,
Solar Energy 181 (2019) 372–378)

___________________________________________________________________________________

Marcelo 
Cappelletti
Universidad Nacional Arturo Jauretche, Buenos Aires, Argentina
mcappelletti@unaj.edu.ar
He has a great skill in solar cell simulation
(Superlattices Microstruct. 123 (2018) 338-348,
Superlattices Microstruct. 107 (2017) 136-143,
Semicond. Sci. Technol. 31 (2016) 115020)


_________________________________________________________________________________


Smagul 
Zh
Karazhanov 
Senior Scientist    
Institute for Energy Technology, Norway
Sector Energy and Environmental Technology
smagulk@ife.no
His papers are devoted to ultrasound-dislocation interaction in silicon barrier structure.
(J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys. 41 (2008) 165107; J. Phys. Chem. Solids 70 (2009) 989–992)

Andriy
B.
Romanyuk
Institute of Physics
University of Basel, Switzerland
andriy.romanyuk@unibas.ch
He is author of works, which are deals with acoustically induced effects in semiconductors.
(J. Appl. Phys. 107 (2010)
114307; J. Appl. Phys. 99 (2006), 034314; Appl. Phys. Lett. 90 (2007),
013118)

Bruno
K.
Meyer
Physical Institute
Justus-Liebig Universitaty, Germany
Bruno.K.Meyer@exp1.physik.uni-giessen.de
He has investigated ultrasound influence on semiconductor structure
(Solid State Commun. 116 (2000) 87–91)

Silke
Steingrube
Department Solar Energy, Institute Solid-State Physics, Leibniz University of Hannover, Appelstr. 2, 30167
Hannover, Germany
steingrube@solar.uni-hannover.de
He has used models of coupled defect level recombination to explain features of solar cell current-voltage characteristics.
(J. Appl. Phys. 110(2011), 014515)


Vishnu
Gopal
Solid State Physics Laboratory, Timarpur, Delhi
110054, India
sspl@ssplnet.org
He has introduced model of dislocation–induced impedance, which has been used in our manuscript.
(IEEE Trans Electron Devices 50(2003), 1220–1226; IEEE Trans Electron Devices 51(2004),1078–1083)

He has a great skill in determination of current mechanisms in semiconductor barrier structures.
(IEEE Trans Electron Devices 51(2004),1078–1083;
J.Appl. Phys. 116 (2014) 084502;
Semicond. Sci. Technol. 16 (2001) 372-376)


Arthur
Medvids
Faculty of Materials Science and Applied Chemistry, 
Riga Technical University, Riga, Latvia
He has investigated ultrasound influence on semiconductor structure
medvids@latnet.lv
(Phys Status Solidi C 13(2016), 793–797)