-What research institutions are involved in this paper?
Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, Kyiv, Ukraine


-How would you describe the method and findings from your paper to an audience not familiar with physics?
The main method is "active" ultrasound.
That is, the use of acoustic waves to change the state of a semiconductor crystal, to effect the electric current.


-In your opinion, what is the new or innovative part of your work?
Use of ultrasound to influence defects in non-piezoelectric crystals.


-What were the major challenges in your work? What surprised you the most?
The main challenge is  to set up an experiment. The experiment should allow to separate the influence of the elastic vibrations, the temperature (heating) and the electric field.
The most surprize is the magnitude of acostically induced effect (tens of percent).



-What do you think will be the subject of your next projects related to this work or for others working within the same space?
To improve the controllability and selectivity of ultrasound effects.


-What impact do you foresee this paper will have on your field?
I hope that this paperk will draw attention to the potential ability of ultrasound to be an active tool to influence on semiconductor structures.


-Are there other potential applications where this procedure be used?
In our opinion, the greatest potential is the use of ultrasound during the formation of semiconductor devices (or during crystal growth).



-Please explain "ideality factor" for a non-scientific audience.
The "ideality factor" reflects the influence of crystal defects, which are located near the srtucrure interface, on the an electric current.


-How does using ultrasound compare to other methods of studying and interacting with material defects, such as electron beam?
As a defect engineering tool, US has the following advantages: 
(i) locality of action due to predominant absorption in the regions of lattice periodicity deviation; 
(ii) selectivity of inﬂuence, which depends on acoustic wave (AW) polarization and AW type; 
(iii) possibility to transform the defect system by applying resonance frequency; and 
(iv) reversibility of the effect of low intensity AW.



-Why is it important for us to gain such a thorough understanding of semiconductor defects?
Defects are decisive for the electrical properties of semiconductor crystals and devices. 
Understanding the defects  behavior and managing  is a key factor in creating new microelectronic devices.



-Please describe the n+–p structure and discuss what types of materials and applications it's used for.
The structure consists of two regions with the different type of majority charge carriers (electrons and holes).
For example, it is  structure of the  solar cells, LEDs, diods.
The crystalline or amorphous semiconductors, organic materials etc are used fo constract n–p structures.