home2 token
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


Interstitial iron and the complexes it forms with
shallow acceptors (B, Al, Ga, In) in silicon are thoroughly studied
and well documented: in p-type Si at room temperature
and in darkness, the positively charged Fe$_i$ is known to
diffuse through the Si lattice to form Coulombic pairs with
negatively ionized acceptors. The pairs can be broken by
intense illumination and/or annealing above 200C \cite{Istratov1999,FeBKinAPL2013}.



Shallow acceptors (B, Al, Ga, In) are effective trapping sites for iron around room temperature in p-Si
due to electrostatic attraction between the negatively charged
acceptors and the positively charged iron ions.
All Fe-acceptor pairs are similar:
complexes have two structural conﬁgurations,
with trigonal and orthorhombic symmetry, and can be broken by
intense illumination and/or annealing above 200C \cite{Istratov1999,FeBKinAPL2013}.



The silicon solar cells constitute about 90% of current global photovoltaic production capacity.
Iron is one of the most relevant, omnipresent, and efficiency-limiting metallic impurities 
in p-type silicon solar cells \cite{Istratov1999,IronSC}. 
Therefore, the methods of defect engineering, aimed at iron, have practical importance.
On the one hand, shallow acceptors (B, Al, Ga, In) are effective trapping sites for iron around room temperature
and in darkness in p-Si
due to electrostatic attraction between the negatively charged
acceptors and the positively charged iron ions.
All Fe-acceptor pairs are similar:
complexes have two structural conﬁgurations,
with trigonal and orthorhombic symmetry, and can be broken by
intense illumination and/or annealing above 200$^\circ$C \cite{Istratov1999,FeBKinAPL2013}.
On the other hand, the back surface field (BSF) and passivated emitter and rear cell (PERC) 
are the most popular designs that have being used in mass-production of c-Si SCs
and both BSF and PERC are mainly  based on boron-doped silicon wafers \cite{SCRev2020,GreenRew2019}.
Therefore the iron-boron pair is one of the most relevant complex to the defect engineering in real SCs.






Iron is an omnipresent, most relevant and efﬁciency-limiting impurity in p-type silicon solar cells. 


-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Why were AWs excited in the samples of 2.4; 4.1; 5.4; 9.0; 14; 18; 31 MHz (longitudinal) or 
0.3 MHz (transverse) with frequency fUS ?. Give a reason. Why not selected substitution atoms?


In our previous works \cite{Olikh2018SM,Olikh2018JAP,OlikhJAP,GORB2020,Olikh:Ultras,Olikh:Ultras2016},
we have shown that megahertz acoustic waves can be an effective tool for defect engineering in silicon structures.
Thus in this work we tried to use such waves to control iron impurities in silicon SCs.
On the other hand,
it is widely known that the efficiency of ultrasound influence on defects 
in semiconductor depends on acoustic wave frequency.
Moreover, the type of frequency dependence is determined by the mechanism of acousto-defect 
interaction \cite{Brailsford,Pavlovich,PeleshchakUJF2016}.
The set of longitudinal wave's frequencies (2.4; 4.1; 5.4; 9.0; 14; 18; 31 MHz) 
was used in our investigation  to evaluate features of 
ultrasound influence on iron migration.
Besides,  the effect of increase in the carrier capture coefficient for defects in silicon SC
is shown \cite{Olikh2018SM} to be intensified in the case of the transverse acoustic waves using.
Accordingly, the transverse waves (0.3~MHz) were used in this investigation as well.
In the case of acoustically-induced (AI) change of capture coefficient, the 
USL causes the change in the complex components distance \cite{Olikh2018SM}. 
In our case of FeB pair association, the AI effect is an opposite and is weakened for transverse waves using.
Therefore, the acceleration of FeB pair association does not deal with iron-boron distance change.

The text was revised
(second paragraph in ``Experimental and Calculation Details'';
page~8, paragraph~2).




Transverse waves,
despite their low frequency, less strongly impact the processes of FeB pair association.
It should be noted that the acoustically-induced change of capture coefficient for defect
deals with the change in the complex components distance and this effect is intensified in the case of 
the transverse waves \cite{Olikh2018SM}.
The opposite features of investigated effect testifies that the AI acceleration of FeB pair 
association does not deal with iron-boron distance change. 




 
How much doping of phosphorus? How do they measure thickness?



The thickness of the wafers was 380~$\mu$m.
A diffusion from the gas phase (POCl$_3$) at 940$^\circ$C was performed on wafers resulting in a $n^+$--emitter layer on
the front side (sheet resistance of about $20-30$~$\Omega/\Box$, thickness of $0.7$~$\mu$m).
In addition, to reduce recombination losses and increase the conductivity of the contact layer,
a $p^+$ layer ($10-20$~$\Omega/\Box$, $0.6$~$\mu$m) was formed by boron diffusion from 
the gas phase (BCl$_3$) at 985$^\circ$C on the rear surface.
The solid and grid aluminum contacts were formed by magnetron sputtering on the rear and front surfaces, respectively.

The layer thicknesses were evaluated by using an annealing  temperature and duration as well as an partial pressure gas.

More detailed information about samples was added 
(first paragraph in ``Experimental and Calculation Details'').


--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Result and discussion: In figure 5, x axis when will it reach minimum? 
Is there any particular reason for selecting 300 to 304K?


The investigations shown that the dependence of $\tau_\mathrm{US}/\tau_{0}$
on ultrasound intensity is close to linear at low $W_\mathrm{US}$.
The increase in $W_\mathrm{US}$ leads to saturation, which correspond to 
$\tau_\mathrm{US}~0.7\tau_{0}$ at $T=340$~K. 
Therefore the minimum (saturation) of curves in Fig.~5 is expected at about $0.3$~W/cm$^2$.
It should be noted that according to Ostapenko and Bell \cite{Ostapenko1995},
the further increase in acoustic strain up to $\xi_\mathrm{US}=10^{-5}$ may lead to 
FeB pair dissosiation and increase in $\tau_\mathrm{US}$.

The temperature range is limited by following reasons.
On the one hand, the investigations shown that the ultrasound influence
on FeB pair association time was weakened with temperature decrease.
And the effect value is about 5% only for $T=300$~K --- see Fig.~6.
Therefore the experiments seem useless at $T<300$.
On the other hand, the portion of interstitial iron atoms that
remain unpaired in the equilibrium state encreases with temperature rise.
According to Wijaranakula \cite{FeB:kinetic}, the concentration of
unpaired iron atom $N_\mathrm{Fe_i,eq}$
depends on temperature, doping level, and concentration of 
all iron impurity atoms $N_\mathrm{Fe,0}$.
The estimations show that at 340~K $N_\mathrm{Fe_i,eq}=0.1N_\mathrm{Fe,0}$.
The further temperature decrease leads to increase in 
$N_\mathrm{Fe_i,eq}/N_\mathrm{Fe,0}$ value and 
to significant decrease in change of short circuit current after intence illumination. 





 