Використані в JAP:
Andriy Romanyuk (University of Basel), 
Sandra Herlufsen (ISFH), 
Nabil Khelifati (Centre de Recherche en Technologie des Semi-conducteurs pour l'Energétique), 
Arthur Medvids (Riga Technical University), 
Fiacre Rougieux (University of New South Wales)


Використані в Appl Phys A:
Ville Vahanissi, 
Smagul Karazhanov

вмкористані в Journal of Materials Science: Materials in Electronics:
Daniel Kropman
Matous Mrovec
Chang Sun
A.K. Uteniyazov
Hannu S. Laine
Sergey V. Bulyarskiy
Teimuraz Mchedlidze
___________________________________________________________

Hannu
S.
Laine
Department of Mechanical Engineering, Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), Cambridge, MA, USA
Department of Electronics and Nanoengineering, Aalto University, Espoo, Finland
hannu.laine@aalto.fi
He is skilled in the behavior of iron in silicon solar cells
(IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 6 (2016) 1094-1102;
physica status solidi (a) 216 (2019), 1900253)


Prof.
Carlos 
del Cañizo
Instituto de Energía Solar, Universidad Politécnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain
Carlos.canizo@ies.upm.es
His papers are devoted to extract defect properties from inexpensive IV measurements of completed devices
(IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 10 (2020) 1532-1537)

Prof.
Sergey 
V.
Bulyarskiy
Institute of Nanotechnology of Microelectronics of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Moscow, Russia
bulyar2954@mail.ru
His papers are devoted to defect in silicon solar cells
(Journal of Applied Physics, 128 (2020) 155702,
Solid State Electronics 160 (2019) 107624)


Teimuraz 
Mchedlidze
Technische Universität Dresden, 01062 Dresden, Germany
teimuraz.mtchedlidze@physik.tu-dresden.de
He is the author of works, which are deals with defect 
(in particular, iron) in silicon solar cells.
(J. Appl. Phys. 116 (2014), 245701; 
Physica Status Solidi (A) 216 (2019), 1900142;
Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells 155 (2016) 38–42)


Matous
Mrovec
Ruhr-Universitat Bochum, Bochum, Germany
matous.mrovec@iwm.fraunhofer.de
His papers are devoted to the behavior of iron in silicon.
(Phys. Rev. B 92 (2015), 115309;
Phys. Rev. B 92 (2015), 195308)


Chang 
Sun
School of Engineering, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT, 2601 Australia
chang.sun@anu.edu.au
He is a specialist in the physics of defects in silicon 
(Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells 187 (2018) 263–272;
Phys. Status Solidi RRL 15 (2021), 2100483)


A.K.
Uteniyazov
Karakalpak State University, Ch. Abdirov Street 1, Nukus 230112, Uzbekistan
abat-62@mail.ru
He is skilled in ultrasonically induced effect in 
semiconductor structure
(Advances in Materials Science and Engineeringthis, 2021, 8836368;
Semiconductor Physics, Quantum Electronics and Optoelectronicsthis, 22(2019), 165–170)

Daniel
Kropman
Tallinn University of Technology, Tallinn, Estonia
daniel.kropman@mail.ee
He has investigated ultrasound influence on defects in  semiconductor structure.
(Phys Status Solidi C 13(2016), 793–797)



Sandra 
Herlufsen
Institute for Solar Energy Research Hamelin, Emmerthal, Germany
herlufsen@isfh.de
She is skilled in defect transformation in silicon solar cells
(Phys. Status Solidi RRL 6 (2012)  1–3,
IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 11 (2021) 890-896)


Nabil 
Khelifati
Centre de Recherche en Technologie des Semi-conducteurs pour l’Energétique, Algiers, Algeria
n.khelifati@gmail.com
His papers are devoted to dissociation and formation of iron–boron pairs in
silicon.
(Phys. Status Solidi A 216 (2019) 1900253,
Journal of Electronic Materials 45 (2016), 5621-5625)


Fiacre 
E. 
Rougieux
School of Photovoltaic and Renewable Energy Engineering, The University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia
ﬁacre.rougieux@unsw.edu.au
He is a specialist in the physics of defects in silicon 
(Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells 187 (2018) 263–272,
IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 11 (2021), 273-281)


Andriy
B.
Romanyuk
Institute of Physics
University of Basel, Switzerland
andriy.romanyuk@unibas.ch
He is author of works, which are deals with acoustically induced effects in semiconductors.
(J. Appl. Phys. 107 (2010)
114307; J. Appl. Phys. 99 (2006), 034314; Appl. Phys. Lett. 90 (2007),
013118)


Arthur
Medvids
Faculty of Materials Science and Applied Chemistry, 
Riga Technical University, Riga, Latvia
He has investigated ultrasound influence on semiconductor structure
medvids@latnet.lv
(Phys Status Solidi C 13(2016), 793–797)

Ville
Vahanissi
Staff Scientist
Aalto University, Espoo, Finland
Department of Micro- and Nanosciences
ville.vahanissi@aalto.fi
He is skilled in the behavior of iron in silicon solar cells
(IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 6 (2016) 1094-1102;
Progress in Photovoltaics: Research and Applications 21 (2013) 1127)

Smagul 
Zh
Karazhanov 
Senior Scientist  
Institute for Energy Technology (IFE), Kjeller, Norway  
Sector Energy and Environmental Technology
smagulk@ife.no
His papers are devoted to ultrasound-defect interaction in silicon barrier structure.
(J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys. 41 (2008) 165107; J. Phys. Chem. Solids 70 (2009) 989–992)


Bruno
K.
Meyer
Physical Institute
Justus-Liebig Universitaty, Germany
Bruno.K.Meyer@exp1.physik.uni-giessen.de
He has investigated ultrasound influence on semiconductor structure
(Solid State Commun. 116 (2000) 87–91)

Silke
Steingrube
Department Solar Energy, Institute Solid-State Physics, Leibniz University of Hannover, Appelstr. 2, 30167
Hannover, Germany
steingrube@solar.uni-hannover.de
He has used models of coupled defect level recombination to explain features of solar cell current-voltage characteristics.
(J. Appl. Phys. 110(2011), 014515)


Vishnu
Gopal
Solid State Physics Laboratory, Timarpur, Delhi
110054, India
sspl@ssplnet.org
He has introduced model of dislocation–induced impedance, which has been used in our manuscript.
(IEEE Trans Electron Devices 50(2003), 1220–1226; IEEE Trans Electron Devices 51(2004),1078–1083)

