Acoustically driven degradation in single crystalline Si solar cell

The experimental investigation of ultrasound influence on the silicon solar cell current-voltage characteristic has been carried out.
The experiments were carried out by  using  longitudinal and transverse ultrasound waves  in the temperature range from 290 to 340~K.
The investigation has revealed the acoustically driven reversible increment of an ideality factor and decrement of a carrier lifetime both in the space charge region and in the solar cell base, a photocurrent, an open--circuit voltage,  a fill factor, and a shunt resistance.
The models of coupled defect level recombination, Shockley--Read--Hall recombination, and dislocation--induced impedance were used to describe the processes in the space charge region,  in the solar cell base, and shunt resistance respectively.
The role of oxide precipitates in an recombination and in an acousto--defect interaction has been discussed.
It has been shown that the acoustically induced increase of carrier capture coefficient of point or extended defects is a reason of observed effects and qualitative model of ultrasound influence has been proposed.

silicon
solar cells
ultrasound influence


Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv
Kyiv


To: Progress in Photovoltaics: Research and Applications Editorial Board
Subject: Article Submit

Dear Editorial Board,

We request to consider a possibility of publication of our article "Acoustically driven degradation in single crystalline Si solar cell" in the journal "Progress in Photovoltaics: Research and Applications".
The findings have not been published previously and are not currently under consideration for publication elsewhere.

Sincerely yours,
Οleg Olikh 
Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv
Kyiv 01601, Ukraine
E-mail: olikh@univ.kiev.ua
