To:
Samantha Tola
Palisades Convention Management
The 2017 II-VI Workshop
411 Lafayette Street, Suite 201
New York, NY 10003

stola@pcm411.com


Copy to:
Paola Caicedo
Sivananthan Laboratories, Inc.
590 Territorial Drive, Unit H
Bolingbrook, IL 60440

pcaicedo@sivananthanlabs.us 




I am proud of chance to present our results at the 2017 U.S. Workshop on the Physics and Chemistry of II-VI Materials.
The Workshop plays a vital role in technological evolution ov II-VI material.
Unfortunately, no much attention is given by the Wokshop to ultrasound, which is powerful tool of semiconductor device engineering.
According to http://www.sheridanprinting.com/pcm/iivi/sessionlist.cfm, only our paper deals with ultrasound
in 2017 Program.
Therefore I am assured that our experimental results will attract interest of colleagues.
In addition it may be a base of future collaboration.


Besides science become successful often due to international cooperation.
According to http://www.sheridanprinting.com/pcm/iivi/sessionlist.cfm, only our group represent Ukraine.
But now Ukraine has considerable economical problems.
Government support of science is negligible practically.
And only You can to support the Ukrainian Physics in our person.
And I would be very grateful if you`ll provide the following aid.

1. Release from Registration Fee. 
This step does not require any financial  investment, as I will be fully satisfied by electronic copy of the Book and will not abuse refreshments.

2. Support travel to the Workshop.
May be student funding is not depleted fully.

Thank you very much in advance for kind consideration of my request.


I believe that I’ll see you in Chicago,
Sincerely,
Oleg Olikh
Associate professor,
Physics faculty,
Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv


Paper to be presented:
Ultrasonic Treatment Effects on CuS1.8 – CdSe Structures
Poster Session (Paper No. P.2)
Co-author: Bogdan Polonsky.

Some References:

1."Ultrasound influence on I–V–T characteristics of silicon Schottky barrier structure,"
O.Ya. Olikh, K.V. Voytenko, R.M. Burbelo, Journal of Applied Physics, 2015, Volume 117, Issue 4, 044505

2."On the mechanism of ultrasonic loading effect in silicon-based Schottky diodes,"
O.Ya. Olikh, K.V. Voytenko,  Ultrasonics, 2016, Volume 66, Pages 1-3 

3."Reversible influence of ultrasound on γ-irradiated Mo/n-Si Schottky barrier structure,"
O.Ya. Olikh, Ultrasonics, 2015, Volume 56, Pages 545-550

4."Features of Ultrasound Absorption by Dislocations in Subgrain-Free Cs0.2Hg0.8Te Crystals,"
I.O. Lysyuk,   Ya.M. Olikh, O.Ya. Olikh,  G.V. Beketov, Ukrainian journal of physics, 2014, Volume 59, Number 1, Pages 50-57

5."Review and test of methods for determination of the Schottky diode parameters",
O.Ya. Olikh, Journal of Applied Physics, 2015, Volume 118, Issue 2, 024502

6."Non-Monotonic -Ray Influence on Mo/n-Si Schottky Barrier Structure Properties,"
O.Ya. Olikh, IEEE Transactions on Nuclear Science, 2013, Volume 60, Issue 1, Part 2, Pages 394-401






To:
Jafar Saniie, General Chair
2014 IEEE International Ultrasonics Symposium - Chicago

Copy to
Jacqueline Hines, Finance Chair
2014 IEEE International Ultrasonics Symposium – Chicago

Erdal Oruklu, Local Chair
2014 IEEE International Ultrasonics Symposium – Chicago

Dear Jafar Saniie:

I am great pleasured to receive information that our abstracts (ID 310 and
ID 616) have been accepted for Poster presentation during the 2014 IEEE
International Ultrasonics Symposium.

I am very interested to attend such principal Conference on the
Ultrasonics, and I would like to present the results of our recent
investigations. It is very important for me. Also I wish to meet
colleagues, to discuss problems of mutual interest and to exchange R&D
proposals for future collaboration on the related subjects.

I need the US Visa and I would be very grateful for personal Official
Invitation Letter to attend the IUS.

I feel very uncomfortable but I have another request. Now Ukraine has
major political and economical problems. And I would be very grateful if
you`ll provide the financial assistance (travel grant and conference fee)
to me, Dr. O. Olikh. Such assistance will allow defending the papers with
ID 310 and ID 616.

Thank you very much in advance for kind consideration of my request.

I believe that I’ll see you in Chicago,
Sincerely,
Oleg Olikh and Co-authors.


BRIEF BIOGRAPHY OF PRESENTING AUTHOR
Oleg Olikh was born in 1974 in Kyiv, Ukraine. He received M.S. in Physics
in 1996 and Ph.D. Solid State Physics in 2001, both from Taras Shevchenko
National University of Kyiv, Ukraine. Now Dr. Oleg Olikh is the associate
professor of Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, Physics
Faculty. He has an extensive background and research experience in field
of Ultrasonic and Semiconductors. He has authored more 50 scientific
publications (Scopus h-index – 4, Scholar Google h-index – 5 (i10 - 1)).

Salutation: Mr.
Title: Dr.
Complete name: Oleg Ya. Olikh
Сomplete mailing address: Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv,
64/13, Volodymyrska Street, Kyiv, 01601, Ukraine
e-mail address: olikh@univ.kiev.ua

Title of papers to be presented:

1. Ultrasonically induced effects in Schottky Barrier Structure depending
on a [gamma]-irradiation
Abstract ID: 310.
Co-author(s): no.

2. New approach to ultrasonic absorption in subgrain-free Cd0.2Hg0.8Te
crystals.
Abstract ID: 616.
Co-author(s): I. Lysiuk, Ya. Olikh.





Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv
64/13, Volodymyrska Street
Kyiv  01601

RE: (Ultrasonic Treatment Effects on CuS1.8 – CdSe Structures)

Dear Dr. Oleg Oleg:

As a reminder your II-VI Workshop presentation is scheduled for the following session:

Poster Session (Paper No. P.2)

Room: Chicago Ballroom

YOUR FOUR-PAGE EXTENDED ABSTRACT, INCLUDING ALL ILLUSTRATIONS, MUST BE RECEIVED BY
AUGUST 25, 2017.

Four-page Extended Abstracts of all papers will be published in the Book of Extended
Abstracts, which will be distributed at the Workshop.  Please include your
telephone, fax, and e-mail address in the author's byline.  To help you with the
preparation of your extended abstract, a list of instructions are posted on the
conference website (www.ii-viworkshop.org).

In order to ensure your abstract will appear as you intend it is strongly advised
that abstracts be submitted as a .pdf file.  If unable to submit as a .pdf file, an
MS Word file will also be acceptable.  Your Extended Abstract should be submitted
online at the link at the bottom of this email. If your link is not working or you
misplace it, please email Samantha Tola (stola@pcm411.com) and she will resend you
the link.  Please insert the above referenced paper number on the title of your
document (i.e.
II-VI paper Session1Paper1.pdf) when submitting your extended abstract.

The Journal of Electronic Materials (JEM) will publish the 2017 U.S. II-VI workshop
papers in its special issue of the peer-reviewed workshop proceedings (usually
around August of the following year). All authors of the invited contributed and
poster presentations will be asked to submit their manuscripts to the workshop
proceedings for peer review online using the link provided by JEM. Each submitted
paper will go through a formal review process. All reviews will occur online in a
secure environment. Letters and comments concerning the papers will be transmitted
via email to the corresponding author. The details of the paper submission process
and the dates for submission will be emailed separately.

PowerPoint slide presentations will be shown at the Workshop by an electronic
projector driven by a laptop computer with a Windows operating system.  To use this
system, you must bring your presentation on a USB and upload your presentation onto
the Workshop computer well before your session begins. If you require other audio
visual equipment, please notify Samantha Tola at (212) 460-8090 x 203, fax:
212-460-5460, email: stola@pcm411.com by September 15, 2017.

Please visit our website (www.ii-viworkshop.org) for more information on the venue,
hotel reservations, invited speakers and workshop particulars.        

Link to submit your Extended Abstract
https://www.sheridanprinting.com/pcm/iivi/iivi_ea.cfm?id=0A020D04