How to Review and Approve Your Manuscript Proof for Publication

    Download your proof and save it to your desktop. Please be sure to check the entire text, captions, equations, and tables.
    Check each graphic in your proof carefully. Annotate the PDF with any required changes.
        NB: The appearance and quality of graphics in the proofs directly reflect how they will appear in the final published paper online. Graphics may have been down-sampled to produce a more manageable file size for researchers to more easily download your published article.
    Indicate any corrections by annotating the proof PDF and saving it to your desktop. Please note: We cannot accept proofs that have been altered using pdf editing programs. To annotate the PDF, open the PDF file, then choose Comment → Annotations.
        If you are using Acrobat Reader X (or later), use the insert text, strikethrough and add note to replace text tools. If you do not have a recent version of Adobe Acrobat Reader or are a Linux user, please see the information provided in footnote No. 1.
        Extensive corrections may warrant Editorial Office review and will delay publication.
        Note that TeX formatting cannot be used in your annotations on the PDF proofs.
    Permissions: The author is responsible for obtaining permission to publish all figures that have already appeared in other published works. Click here for further instructions:
    To upload and approve your annotated proof, return to the proof site. Please note that this is your final proof and so additional corrections cannot be accepted after upload. You will receive an email message confirming receipt of your corrections.

Questions about Author Select/Open Access

If you have chosen to participate in AIP Publishing's Author Select open-access publishing initiative, please read the following carefully.

You should have recently received an e-mail containing a URL unique to your article where you can submit your payment. If you have not submitted a payment or have billing questions, please call us at +1 800-344-6909 (press 2 when prompted) or e-mail us at pcr@aip.org. Please have the AIP ID number of your article at hand for us to assist you.
Contact Information

If you encounter problems with either downloading page proofs or uploading your proof corrections, send an e-mail to jap@aip.org. It is important to include the AIP ID code number in the subject line of your message.

Thank you for your support of journals published by AIP Publishing.

1 For PC and Mac Users: We recommend that you have a recent version of Adobe Acrobat Reader (Free): "X" is the earliest version we can accommodate; later versions of Acrobat Reader are preferred. Adobe Acrobat Standard or Adobe Acrobat Professional can also be used. [Note: These products are available from the Adobe website: http://www.adobe.com.] Versions are available for PC and Mac users. For help in using any of these tools, follow this link: http://helpx.adobe.com/support.html .
For Linux Users: Most Linux users should be able to annotate their PDFs using the application "Xournal." To do so: (1) save the PDF proofs to your computer; (2) open Xournal; (3) click on "File," then "Annotate PDF" and select the proof; (4) annotate the PDF; and (5) select "Export to PDF." 