0000-0003-0633-5429 
olegolikh@knu.ua
e2662421O
e2662421O% - Heliyon

olegolikh@knu.ua
e2662421O% - Energy Report

Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells
olikh - user name
e2662421O

Dr. Hab.

defects
solar cell
ultrasound
metaheuristic algorithms
semiconductor structures


Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, Kyiv, Ukraine


Estimation of parameters for solar cells with S-shaped current-voltage characteristics using meta-heuristic algorithms

A survey of meta-heuristic algorithms for parameter extraction of next-generation solar cells with S-shaped I-V curves

A test of meta-heuristic algorithms for parameter extraction of next-generation solar cells with S-shaped current-voltage curves

Identifying the parameters of photovoltaic (PV) models based on measured current-voltage (IV) characteristic curves 
is crucial for simulating, evaluating, and controlling PV systems.
IV characteristics of new-generation solar cells (SCs) often exhibit an S-shaped deformation.
In this paper, the potential of using meta-heuristic algorithms
to solve the parameter estimation problems of PV cells
with S-shaped IV characteristics has been explored.
The parameter estimation has been performed within the framework of the opposed two-diode model.
A total of 14 algorithms from various classes were implemented
to extract the SC parameters from synthetic IV curves, which were generated with a range of parameter values.
The obtained results have been compared using nonparametric statistical methods,
including Wilcoxon signed-rank test for pairwise comparisons,
Friedman, Friedman Aligned, and Quade tests for multiple comparisons,
and post-hoc Finner, Holm, Hochberg, Holland,  Shaffer, and Nemenyi procedures.
Research has demonstrated that utilizing a squared error-based fitness function offers clear advantages in tackling a provided problem.
Comprehensive results and analyses indicate that STLBO and ADELI algorithms have highly competitive performance in terms of accuracy and reliability.


S-shaped IV characteristics; Opposed two-diode model; Parameter estimation; Meta-heuristic algorithms; Nonparametric statistical procedure; Solar cell models


Yimin
Zhang 
Shenyang University of Chemical Technology,
Equipment Reliability Institute, Shenyang 110142, China
ymzhang@mail.neu.edu.cn
He is skilled in meta-heuristic algorithms
(Information Sciences 472 (2019) 180–202,
Applied Soft Computing 141 (2023) 110232)


Kang 
Li
University of Leeds,
School of Electronic and Electrical Engineering,  Leeds, LS2 9JT, UK
k.li1@leeds.ac.uk
He is adept at solving optimization problems.
(J. Hydrogen Energy 39 (2014) 3837–3854,
Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment, 119 (2023), 103726)


Rebecca 
Saive
University of Twente
Institute for Nanotechnology, Enschede 7522 NB, The Netherlands 
r.saive@utwente.nl
She is skilled in PV device with S-shaped IV characteristics
(IEEE J. Photovolt. 9 (2019) 1477–1484,
Prog Photovolt  Res Appl. 2023, 1–9;  https://doi.org/10.1002/pip.3700)


Ripon 
K. 
Chakrabortty
University of New South Wales,
School of Engineering and IT, Canberra, Australia
r.chakrabortty@adfa.edu.au
His papers are devoted to solar cell parameter estimation
(Energy Conversion and Management 227 (2021) 113491,
Int. J. Int. SystemsOpen 36 (2021), 4592) 

Belen 
Arredondo
Universidad Rey Juan Carlos
Área de Tecnología Electrónica, C/ Tulipán s/n, 28933 Móstoles, Spain 
belen.arredondo@urjc.es
He applied opposed two-diode model to IV curves analyse
(Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells 176 (2018) 397–404)